We are in the middle or high school, and we're going to have a youth group, and we can head
out right now.
So I have been having the privilege of meeting you here.
My name is Brian, and I'm the pastor.
I'm so glad that you have joined us, and that's what we've asked you to have in this community
and church.
I'm so glad when people use the gifts and abilities of God as healing and spiritual
at the church, as Sophie was singing and doing sign language, I couldn't help.
It was awesome.
I love what you said.
I couldn't help with thinking a few years ago, at Nelson Mandela's funeral, there was an
interpreter for the funeral service, and it turns out that the interpreter didn't know
sign language.
That's pretty awkward, right?
So I was like, as Sophie was doing, I'm like, I don't know sign language, so how do I
accept someone, whether or not they know?
So, if Sophie does indeed know sign language, praise the Lord, if she was just expressing
her worship to the Lord, also praise the Lord.
So, I was like, eww, what?
This dude was standing, like, steps away from President Barack Obama, it seems like, speaking
at Nelson Mandela's funeral.
I'm like, did we lend his background to, or just whether, anyway, that has nothing to do
as well, I'm going to talk about this before I'm just, I couldn't do it out of my head.
So, there's been a theme in worship this morning about the consistent faithfulness of God.
As I've been preparing for my sermon this week, I can't get in this picture, and I didn't
know when I was going to use it, or how I was going to use it in my sermon, but I feel
like it's a great thing to start with.
I feel like somebody in the room might need to hear this before we even actually use the
passage of the picture that we're going to be talking about this morning, and that is,
my son's nine months old, we're about to get into that phase where I'm trying to teach
them how to walk, right?
Thank you for that, looking forward to that.
And as I think about the consistent character of God, and his desire to forgive us, and his
unending love for us, I get this picture of a baby learning to walk, and he's falling down
repetitively.
Those of you that's taught me how to walk, you know this happens, right?
They get up, they take a step or two, and they fall.
And if you're a good parent, what do you do?
How dare you?
You fall?
Don't you know how to walk, can't you figure it?
No, if you're a good parent, you exhort them, and you open up your arms wide to them.
And I just, as we're talking about the consistent character of God, I don't care if you've been
walking with the Lord for 50 years.
If you are still falling flat on your face, he is not looking down on your condemnation.
He's inviting you to stand back up, to be embraced in his loving arms, and take the next step.
And if you fall again, guess what?
Loving, forgiveness, and kindness.
So I don't know who's in here who needs to hear that he's been falling on their face over
and over and over again.
And I don't know what kind of parent upbringing you had.
I don't know if you've imposed that on the God of the universe.
And you think whenever you screw up, whenever you fall again, that he's looking down on you.
He's giving him a condemnation, and you can't believe you haven't figured it out yet.
It's a lie for me now.
That's his character.
His very name means that he was, is, and always will be who he was, is, and always will be.
And that's that God's love and capacity and grace and mercy, yes, and justice, but that love of his passion is eager to forgive you if you would just put your hands up.
And we'll see you next time, and we'll see you next time.
John actually has the most detailed description of the final week of Jesus' life.
So here's how we're going to kick this series back up, leading into Easter, just to kind of really tie a bow in the book of the Gospel of John.
But for now, we're halfway through this section of our series.
We've covered five signs and two IAMs.
Today, we're going to cover a bonus IAM statement.
It's actually not in the seven IAM statements that we kind of classically think about in the Gospel of John.
As you read the book of John, some of you have been writing it out, hammering it out.
Whoever you are and you read, God bless you, you're the same, right?
I love it.
There's like a small group of people that are writing it out.
But if you were to do that, you would see that there's like glances of IAMs all throughout the Gospel of John.
There's actually three different categories of IAMs.
We're focusing on the seven declared statements of Jesus Christ as IAM, the Deceptive, IAM, the Game, IAM, the Bible, the world, IAM, the way, the truth, and the life.
And he's declared a statement that there's other types of IAM statements where someone will ask him a question and he'll respond with just like, I am.
The most famous one is probably the Samaritan woman after well.
She says, when the Messiah comes, he'll teach us everything.
And Jesus says, oh yeah, he, I'm the Messiah, right?
And then the one that we're going to look at today is like, it's like, standing on his own, and I would say it's the kind of interpretive key.
It's the thing that gives depth of meaning to all of the other IAM statements.
Like, on their own, the seven IAM statements are extremely powerful.
But this one gives us true, it gives us clarity, actually, that what Jesus is doing is not just giving a resume for himself when he says,
I am the good shepherd, I am the good shepherd, I am the good shepherd, I am the right of the world.
He's not just giving his resume, he's actually connecting his resume to the very personal name of God.
And without this passage, we would just kind of be assuming that that's what he's doing.
But with this passage, I think we have certainty and clarity that he's doing that.
So, if you've been raised in the church, you've probably already made this connection with Adam and the personal name of God.
But we all have different levels of knowledge and understanding.
So, we're going to kind of get to this bonus IAM statement and unpack exactly what it means for us, for all of each of us.
Does that sound good?
Okay.
Let me pray in the last step.
Father, we are so grateful that you are, that you were, that you forever will be who you are.
That can be said of no other being in all of creation.
You are eternally consistent from beginning to end in what you have been, you will be.
What you are, you will always be.
May we fully grasp the meaning of that for our own relationship with you and for our perception of what eternity will be.
Okay, as we echo the praises of the angels who bow down before you for eternity, for holy, holy, holy, holy, is the Lord of my life.
In Jesus' name right there.
Amen.
So, if you have your Bibles, your apps, you want to follow along, we're going to be going to separate it.
It is in long passage.
With lots of details and lots of things going on, obviously I don't have time to do all of those things.
And so, I'm going to just try to go as fast as we can through the meat of the passage so that we can spend some time focusing on the one statement at the very end of the passage.
So, I am assuming that many of us in the room have had a similar experience to the one that I'm on the back of this side.
It's a sobering one.
Some of you maybe have even experienced it personally in your own lives.
But, unfortunately, as a counselor who has the privilege and honor of doing weddings, I have the unfortunate and sobering experience of, at times, of doing three-year-old counseling with a couple and walking through all of the depth and meaning of what marriage is with this couple.
Only two, a few years later, realize that they're divorced and can't even be in the same room with one of us here.
Right?
I think most of us have some kind of relationship to this experience where we attend the wedding, we see people that we love, make confidence with one another, that they're going to love each other till death, do them part.
Only two, a few years later, see that relationship settled.
No couple things at the altar was that designed out for.
So, what happens?
How do they get to know?
Well, each situation is different, but I would argue that oftentimes in the combination of a couple of different factors, stubbornness, right?
Stubbornness often adds to that problem.
Deception.
You don't, maybe the person who gave you the vows lied to you.
They said something that's going to be true and something different was true.
Or is it genuine misunderstandings about what one another, who one another is and what they want for the future?
And I share this story because we're going to see a very similar experience between a group of Jewish people and Jesus,
who's got that warped speed.
But like marriage, all marriage doesn't make a decent amount of time to break down to that level.
But what we're going to see is a group of Jewish people who believe in Jesus.
Look at verse 31.
This is where we'll start.
It says,
So Jesus said to him.
The Jews who have believed him.
This is a group of people who begin to believe in Jesus.
And it's simply like 27 verses later in verse 59.
At least, maybe not the entire group, but at least some of these Jews who have believed in Jesus just abstains to throw at him.
We see this.
This is crazy.
This is a warped speed like things split.
So how does this happen?
How do this group of Jews begin to believe in Jesus?
And nearly 27 verses later, they pick up signs to everybody with him.
That's why I want to say this one thing.
We're going to figure out what happened.
How did this happen?
And what might we learn?
From this encounter.
Because here's what happens when you read the Scriptures.
At least, if you read the Scriptures, you're anything like me.
You look at the Jews who believed.
You're not clueless at all.
And you're like,
That's the Ganges.
You know, how did they not see?
How did?
We tend to read ourselves into the positive parts of Scripture.
We make ourselves the heroes of the text.
Or at least we don't really connect ourselves into villains.
We're good Bible-believing Christians, right?
In the context, these are good Bible-believing Jews.
You and I, if we were to put, if we were to insert ourselves into the story, we should insert ourselves into the story of the Jews.
This is a sobering warning for those of us who are good Bible-believing Christians.
Is it possible that we often have the same experience with Jesus?
When we sometimes experience who He is and what He's saying to us, we're stubborn and rebellious.
And when He tells us things that we should obey, we reject them.
And even at times, take us homes to get them again.
Right?
So, verse 31.
You guys uncomfortable yet?
Let's see.
Me too.
So, Jesus said to the Jews who have believed in Him,
if you abide in my word.
Remember when we covered at the very beginning of this year, the word belief isn't just intellectual agreement.
Right?
Like, it's agreement and action.
It's trust and obey.
And so, Jesus says, okay, you believe in me.
Let me help you understand what it actually means to believe in me.
What it means to believe in me is to abide in my word.
And if you do that, you are my disciples and you will know its truth and its truth will set you free.
This echoes back to the jealous purpose statement in the gospel that if you believe in Jesus, who he really is,
you'll have abundant life and honor to tell life in the future.
Jesus says, if you abide in my word, you'll know the truth and the truth will set you free.
You'll have this abundant life.
Okay, so, they believe in Jesus, Jesus' first statement to the master they believe, what do you think they're responsible?
I believe Jesus.
That's awesome.
We love to do the thing that you're asking us to do.
Yes.
They swear to be free.
They answered him, we are offspring of Abraham and have never been enslaved to anyone.
How is it that you say we will become free?
Do you, me, any of us, the first thing Jesus says to us, we're like, no, no thanks.
Not in Jesus.
Do you know who I am?
Do you understand what's going on in my life?
So, the Jews immediately responded with stubbornness and unwillingness to accept the first thing that Jesus comes on their mouth after they believe.
Is that me?
Is that you?
Is that us?
Sometimes, right?
Their response exposes that they're unwilling to accept Jesus' word.
It says, freedom.
We're descendants of Abraham.
We've never been enslaved to anyone.
No.
That is the future of this passage of Christ that's going through the entire Old Testament history.
We're laughing right now, right?
Because if you know your Bibles at all, click to the second book of the Bible.
Real quick, we'll just look at the heaven.
What's it called?
Exodence from the life.
Jesus, the nation, Israel, has been enslaved multiple times throughout the history.
And so, these people that aren't willing to accept Jesus' teaching, because they're stubborn and rebellious, and they're unwilling to accept the true need for a Redeemer.
The true need for a Savior.
They are unwilling to receive Jesus' words.
And I love what Jesus does oftentimes.
When people come back to Jesus' physical, listen to himself.
Totally knows what they're saying.
He's using something.
So, he's not even going to engage with them on this level.
He answers them.
Two and two, they'll say to you, everyone who practices sin is enslaved to sin.
The slaves, there's not remaining in the house forever.
The son remains forever.
So, if the son sets you free, you will be free indeed.
I know that you are offspring of any man, yet you seek to kill me because of my words.
They find no place in you.
I speak of what I have seen as my father, and you do what you have told us from your father.
The conversation is escalating very quickly, right?
Jesus is like, yeah, maybe, first of all, you don't know Jesus' history.
If you did, you would know that you were slaves.
But I'm not even talking about physical slavery.
I'm talking about spiritual slavery.
Anyone who practices sin, anyone who continues to disobey the things that God wants for them,
is a slave to that sin.
Isn't it sobering, Lord, into all of us that have patterns and areas of unhealth and sin in our lives?
Jesus says, that is slavery.
You're not truly free.
You're never completely going to experience the abundant life that Jesus wants for you
if you make a habit, a test of sin.
But the question is, what issues in your life are terribly ignoring because it's easy to do my life as well as this and to deal with some?
This is the first step of the way, right?
We've got to acknowledge that we have a problem in order to deal with the problem.
And Jesus comes to the believing Jews and says, you guys have a problem.
And they say, no, we don't.
We're good.
We're free.
We don't need your freedom.
We've never been afraid to do it.
I think a lot of us, we love the idea of following Jesus.
But when the rubber meets the road, we're too stubborn to actually listen and obey.
It's easy to agree with Jesus in the abstract.
But when he starts pointing out the haters in our lives for the reading today, it's a stubborn way to not.
And I need sense because this is not working out the way that's all I want to think.
Verse 31.
So, Abraham is our father.
Jesus says to me, if you were Abraham's children, you would be doing the works that Abraham did.
But now you seek to kill me, and then you will have told me the truth that I heard from God.
This is not what Abraham did.
You are doing the works of your father.
They said to him, we were not born in sexual immorality.
We have one father, even God.
So, so far, they're like, hey, we're children of Abraham.
Jesus puts us back on that.
And they're like, okay, well, we're definitely children of God.
We are children of Yahweh.
Jesus says to them, if God were in your father, you would love me.
For I came from God, and I am here.
I came out of my own accord, but he who sent me.
Why do you not understand what I said?
It's because you cannot bear to hear my word.
It's about to get real intense, real fast.
I told you this conversation happens at height to speak.
You are of your father, the devil.
I think I wonder why people kill Jesus.
But we read out a lot of the drama.
We read out a lot of the weightiness of what Jesus is saying.
We read these beautiful aspects of his laughter, his hearing, and his eloquent things that he says.
He says, you are children of the devil.
If he was a murderer from the beginning, he does not stand in truth, because there is no strength in him.
When he lies, he speaks out of his very character.
We talked about the character of God being consistent from the beginning to end.
The character of the devil is to lie, steal, kill, and destroy.
Because he is a liar and a father of lies.
But because I tell you the truth, if you don't believe me, which one of you convicts me of sin?
I tell you the truth, I do not believe you.
Whoever is God hears the words of God.
The reason why you do not hear the name is that you are none of God.
The first pattern I see in the Jewish leaders of seven.
They're rejecting the freedom.
We don't need freedom.
We're children of Abraham.
Jesus engages in a deeper level of conversation.
They move from stubbornness to deception.
They are being deceived by thinking that they have some moral standing before God because of their religious identity.
They can face their bloodline back to Abraham, so they must be special.
They must have this connection with God.
We are children of Abraham and children of God.
And Jesus says, if you were children of Abraham, you would do what Abraham did.
You would have faith.
You would believe.
You would follow.
You would do the things that God tells you to do.
But you're not doing those things.
You're being deceived into submitting your life, worshiping another God, mainly the devil.
He says, you're being deceived.
You're believing a lie.
You're worshiping a God, a living a God.
You think this whole dialogue reminds me of my favorite Christmas movie that you wrote a picture here.
Buddy the elf.
Right?
Jesus is like, Buddy the elf.
This isn't Santa.
I'm no Santa.
This is not Santa.
You are a lion.
You sit on a throne of lies.
You smell like geese and shoes, right?
And when we think about the devil, don't think about red-scaling out with a pitchfork.
Right?
Like, this is not what the Bible talks about when he talks about the devil.
The devil is a spiritual being who exists to lie, kill, and destroy.
He exists to deceive God's creation into believing less than what God wants for them.
God creates Satan's counterfeit.
So, it's not, there's not, like, one version of Satan.
There's, like, you know, like there's every mall you ever go through, there's a fake thing in him.
That's how Satan works.
He spends these distortions of God all over.
And what the Jews are worshiping is their worst thing, their religious identity, their morality, their religion.
That's just one God that Satan uses to deceive people into wanting less than what God is.
So, maybe for you, maybe you're in here, and that's you.
Like, religion is your thing.
You know, you get up every single morning and post on Instagram, and you're in your devotion with Jesus,
even though you absolutely don't want to spend time with Jesus or just do it, because, like, that's who you are, right?
Like, my, maybe that's you.
But I don't think that's a lot of us in the room.
I think that a lot of us in the room has different guys that we're accepting above Jesus.
We're accepting a ton of sin rather than the real sin.
Jesus, like Buddy D.L., says, I know the real sin.
This is not the real sin.
You're missing out.
Many of us are being deceived at one level or another to put our trust in something other than the one who created us,
whether it's religion, material things, career success, your appearance or your physical health,
something extreme is not posting your Bible to those things, but instead you're posting how great you love.
Guess what?
You're going to get old.
Can I get an amen, somebody?
And if you're God, like, it's the thing that you find your identity and it's how sick you are,
what's going to happen in 10, 20, 30, 40 years?
If you put your identity, if you find your freedom and your career success,
guess what happens when your career gets ripped out from underneath you?
If you fit your identity, if you find your freedom in your family unit and how wonderful everything is
and how good life has gone because you guys live on the cul-de-sac and all of the amenities of your life development
and this is what your life is, what happens when your 16-year-old kid runs away
because they don't want to be in your home anymore?
If you find your identity in these things, if your spiritual freedom,
if your freedom in your life is wrapped around something less than the creator of the universe,
then it can always be taken away from you.
But if you root your identity in a relationship with the creator of the universe,
then no matter what happens, you can have peace in the midst of difficult circumstances.
So, they're stubborn, they're deceived, and honestly, really the culmination of this
picking up of the stones to kill Jesus is really a misunderstanding of who Jesus is.
That's what I'm saying.
In verse 48, the Jews answered him,
Are we not right in saying that you are a Samaritan and you have a demon?
I've done a bunch of study on this because nobody can really point to any history or anything.
I think they're just making stuff up because I'm just a little stick.
You guys watch the news lately?
Right?
This is a tactic that you use when you're in this level of conversation,
that is where it's conversation with somebody, right?
Fine, you're a Samaritan and you have a demon.
You have a Samaritan, whatever.
I do not know the demon, but I have a Samaritan, my father, and you design me in me.
Yes, I do not seek my own glory.
There is one who seeks it, and he is a devil.
He is truly so ready to say to you if anyone can find it, he will never see death.
So, remember our purpose in Germany.
Believing in who Jesus is will lead to abundant life now and eternal life in the future.
First thing Jesus says, if you abide in my truth, then you will know its truth, and that will set you free.
If you remain in Jesus, you have abundant life now.
And then he says, later, truly, truly, I say to you, when you teach my words,
we'll never see death, eternal life, and death future.
But you say to him, now we know that you have a demon.
Abraham died, as did the prophets.
Yet you say, if anyone keeps my words, he will never face death.
So, you're saying, the heroes of the faith, all of the most godly characters,
the most godly people in our history,
we've all died.
And you're saying that if people trust you, believe in you, they want to see death.
And this is the crux of the question.
The whole point, the whole conversation is contendered to this one question in verse 53.
Jesus said, who do you make yourself happy to be?
Who are you?
Who do you think you are?
Abraham, God, the prophets died.
They asked you, you're saying that if we just abide in you, they will never face death.
What are you actually trying to say about yourself?
Ultimately, we find Jesus' answer to this question in verse 58.
Jesus said to them, truly, truly, I'll say to you, before Abraham was on heaven.
And if you grew up in church, you're already connecting to God.
You're already making the connection to women.
Moses has a conversation with the God of the Bible.
The first time anybody ever asked the God who created the universe what his name was,
and his response is, guess what?
I don't know.
Did you say to Jesus, who do you think you are?
And since we're on the comedy scene for this morning, this really reminded me of the office
going to say that, okay, at least a lot of you will get destroyed, so let's see if you have to
go on and say, all right, Michael Scott, you missed 100% of the shots you don't take.
Wayne Gresge, Michael Scott, right?
So Michael Scott, close Wayne Gresge as if he is Wayne Gresge.
You see the comedy in this?
All right, it's true, it's funny, but ultimately, I want to think about this.
This is how these believing Jews would have viewed what Jesus was doing.
You're claiming, you're quoting the Great One as if you are the Great One,
and this is exactly what Jesus is doing.
You want to know who I am?
I am exactly for Yahweh.
Jesus is God in the flesh.
This is what John 1 is all about.
In the beginning was the Word.
The Word was with God.
The Word was God.
The Word became flesh and dwelt among us.
Jesus said, I am equal, same to Yahweh, God of the Old Testament.
Let's look at it.
Exodus chapter 3.
Just in order to really understand the audacity of what Jesus is saying.
We'll have to turn on some of these just real quick.
There's actually chapter 3.
So, burning the blood, see this.
Okay.
What I'm learning more and more about people that come to King, which I love,
is I assume knowledge that doesn't exist.
So, I've been having a conversation with somebody, and I'm just like, I just want to do, um,
I can't remember, oh, Daniel on the line.
I'm like, well, you know Daniel.
You know Daniel.
So, I say, well, you know what's going on here with Moses.
A lot of you probably don't.
So, really quick, burning bush.
Moses is in the burning bush.
He goes in this burning bush.
The God of the Jews says to Moses, I've put to you, and I'm going to send you to Egypt
to set my people free.
And Moses is going to come up with every excuse that he can come up with to not do the thing
that God wants to do.
And so, finally, he's going to run out of excuses, and he says to God, okay, if you
if I obey you, if I do the thing that you're calling me to do, um, and I tell the people
of Israel, and I say to them, the God of your fathers has sent me, well, they're going
to ask me what your name is.
This is, like, the level of excuse he's gotten to, like, so, when they ask me what your name
is, what should I tell them?
And God says, I am poetic.
Which, on the surface, is like a really over-spiritual, poetic, confusing statement that means nothing.
But, as he really thinks about it, as he thinks about the thing that God is saying about himself,
is he's saying, I am the preexistent, internal, consistent being of all of the universe.
There's a whole one question saying, essentially, what Yahweh was saying, what God was saying,
is I am the existence of the universe.
Whatever it is, I am before and behind and beside everything that is in the universe.
When you want to know who I am, I want to say what was, is, and will be to come.
I am consistent in my nature and my character.
Whatever Yahweh was, he is and he will be.
He's never been changed.
He says to Moses, tell the people of Israel, the Lord, the God of the fathers, the God of Abraham,
the God of Isaac, the God of Jacob, I sent me to you.
This is my name for heaven, and thus I need to be remembered throughout all of the generations.
He's speaking such a sacred, personal name of God that the Jews wouldn't even say it out loud.
And Jesus is clearly as possible here stating that he is one with the God of Abraham, the God of Isaac, and the God of Jacob.
He's not just a prophet or a rabbi, he is the greatest I am.
Believing Jews, or at least some of them, clearly understanding the claim that he's making because they pick up stones to kill him.
This is the most blasphemous thing that you could possibly do, is make yourself act to be the God of the universe.
Well, I've helped him ask you someone who's in the name of Yahweh.
He says, what Yahweh essentially meant to the people is that I am and will continue to do what I am and will forever be.
God is created, he will forever be created if he is loving, he will forever be loving.
If he is kind, merciful, if he blasphemy, if he's bloated, injured, and abandoned, and saved God's love, he will always be those things.
God's meaning and gives us confidence that whatever is true about him will always be true about him.
You know, although the Scriptures are filled with an incomprehensible amount of truth about God, including the seven hundred statements.
So, from now on, we're covering the rest of the seven hundred statements.
When he hears Jesus say, I am the good shepherd, he is saying, Yahweh is the good shepherd.
God has always been, is, and will always be a good shepherd.
I am the light of the world.
God has always been, is, and will always be the light of the world.
You following?
So, there's, there's, John later says, if I were to write everything down, every book in the entire universe wouldn't be able to communicate what's true about God.
So, if I was to do a message on the consistent character of God, who always was, always is, always will be, will be, and so we're all done.
You guys don't want that, do you?
Okay.
Come on.
Wow.
All right.
We're going to be here for a while.
Let me see.
So, we're going to, we're going to focus on one specific capacity of God that I think this passage clearly states that is true of God from the beginning of the beginning.
God is, will be, and always was, like, this is the power of some of us.
And this is the whole point of today's message.
If you don't take anything else away, take this away.
All of it, was, is, and will always be, inviting His creation out of slavery that leads to death, and in history when it leads to life.
This is the consistent character and nature of God from the beginning.
If you think about creation, God's creation out of the need in the garden, and He said, it lives in this garden, it's perfect, it's beautiful, it is the definition of abundant life.
You will enjoy this for all eternity.
If you just trust me, if you abide in my words, God, if I go out of it, if you just, if you just, if you just abide in my words, you're just freedom and love.
But just what I mean is the same thing that you and I do, and did, and will always do.
So, stubborn, deceived, misinterpreted who God is and what He's like.
And because of that, instead of walking on streets bringing them, at least the life, these, at least the group of these Jews pick up their standards as a curl, don't have, and the sun.
So, our question for you in our life is, is there any area in our lives where we're experiencing slavery, like coins, currents, tunnels, of course putting up some habits, that are reported in our life, that are keeping us from experiencing the freedom that God wants to live?
I ask you this week to examine your life, think about the patterns of your life, and say, is there something, are there areas in my life where I'm not experiencing the freedom that God wants for me, that God has always been inviting me into?
And if there are, why?
I'd ask you to start with very extreme that I struggle with, but God might reveal something else to you.
Is it because you're struggling when you're disobeying the things that you know to be true about God?
And how often is that true about God?
How often do we walk in slavery because we know what God wants for us, but we refuse to obey?
Maybe the enemy of God is to steams you into believing that you are experiencing freedom.
It's because you've placed your worship in something less than the God of the universe, and it's bringing you some pleasure and satisfaction right now.
Maybe the enemy of God is giving you the invitation that God has given you.
So, unbelievers, you're here and you haven't yet followed Jesus.
You haven't yet chosen to walk after him.
The illustration of the problem I'm lying to you is that the God of the universe is not going to have to grow your life, inviting you.
You're not a slavery and into freedom.
My question to you is where are you at home?
And if you haven't let him in yet, is it because of your stubbornness?
You've been deceived.
Or maybe that you misunderstand your invitation.
See, I believe some of you in this room are not letting Jesus into your life.
You're not opening the door to him because you don't know who he is.
You think that he's unkind and unloving and that he wants to take from you and that he's just this cosmic pill of joy that's going to give you all of these rules.
So, Yahweh wants, is, and will always be inviting you into freedom that leads to life.
If you have any other idea about God, then you're misunderstanding what he wants for you, who he is for you.
So, is it possible that you're not letting God into your life yet because you misunderstand what he actually wants for you?
I'm hoping my third will be this morning.
And as we study through the Gospel of John, you will experience the consistent character of Yahweh in Jesus.
And that you will realize how much Yahweh extremely loves you, is waiting to forgive you, and the one for the relationship with you that leads to your abundant life, now, and eternal life.
For those of us that are followers of Jesus, we've left the God of the universe into the house of our lives.
The real space that I have for you is, I think, so often we as believers, we look down into our home, we go out of our house, and we say, make yourself a home.
And guess what he does?
We make yourself a home, which means he walks into your bedroom.
It opens up the drawer or two, and what do we do?
No, not that one.
No, no, no, don't touch that.
Don't go that way.
That closet is off-limits, Jesus.
I can't help but wonder how many of us who have given Jesus control over our lives still aren't experiencing the true freedom that he has for us.
Because when he infiltrates our lives, and when he says to us, if you are above me, if you will remain in my words, and we say, you know, most of them, I like a lot of what you have to say to me, but how often is there areas of our lives where he's calling us to obedience?
And we're like, no, no, no, no, that's not that.
Or we religiously come to fix it.
We're like, all right, all right, guys.
Get out of the closet.
Go back to the living room.
Let me bring the closet up.
And then you can come to the closet.
Now, he does the command.
He wants to be a person with us.
He's a priest and a priest.
So, my intention to this week would be to ask yourself, are there areas of life where I'm not walking in the freedom that God has for you now?
Yes, so.
Why?
Am I just disorganized?
Am I not doing the things he's trying to do?
Am I being distingued?
Am I putting my hope in something less than who he really is?
Am I misunderstanding?
I know that I'll tell you, Mr. Lord, if you would, you know, I don't have time to give you the details.
I always wanted to because I tried to be vulnerable with you.
And the Lord really called me out on a couple of things a few weeks ago.
And I was going to give you all the gory details.
I don't know.
For me, the Lord revealed some areas of my life where slavery still is.
And some of those were because I was just being stubborn and not doing the thing that I know I needed to do.
Some of them was because I was putting my hope in the wrong thing.
And can I be honest with you?
This was a couple of weeks ago when I was cruising on here.
I know you were able to say thank you.
Please speak to us.
I'm still struggling with some of those things.
That's okay.
But what's not okay is for the Lord to tell me those things.
And he says, I'm not just blazing.
Here you are in.
So I'm a gold Christian, Bible-believing guy.
I'm a pastor.
I don't need your spring day.
I'm free.
I'm not free.
I'm not slavery.
And the community of the universe is inviting me into freedom.
Because I don't think the universe is inviting you into freedom.
He was, he is, and he will always be.
Inviting his creation.
All that slavery that leads to God.
And then the freedom that leads to God.
Someone would be able to come back up so we could sing the praise of that song again.
But Yahweh is worthy, that he was worthy, he is worthy, he always will be worthy.
As we reflect on the character and nature of God, may we?
Can I just say these words, but may we believe them and they get our belief and they will lead to action.
Worthy you are there.
Worthy you are.
Worthy you forever will be.
Amen.